http://www.amandafoundation.org/privacy-policy

Adoption Successes
Privacy Policy  Revised 12/06/2019Who we areOur website address is: https://AmandaFoundation.org (hereinafter: "the website")What personal data we collect and why we collect itWe collect information about you when you sign-up for our newsletter and when you make a donation to us.What we collect and storeWhile you visit our site, we’ll track location, IP address and browser type.When you make a donation, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, company name, email address, phone number. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:Send you communicationsRespond to your requests, including donations and complaintsProcess donationsComply with any legal obligations we haveImprove our website offeringsSend you marketing messages, if you choose to receive themWe generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store donor information for 7 years for tax and accounting purposes. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.Who on our team has accessMembers of our administration team have access to the information you provide us, such as:Newsletter subscription information like your name, and email address, andDonor information like your name, email address, company name, and phone number information.Our team members have access to this information to help process donations, send marketing messages, and support you.Google Web FontsFor uniform representation of fonts, this page uses web fonts provided by Google. When you open a page, your browser loads the required web fonts into your browser cache to display texts and fonts correctly.For this purpose your browser has to establish a direct connection to Google servers. Google thus becomes aware that our web page was accessed via your IP address. The use of Google Web fonts is done in the interest of a uniform and attractive presentation of our plugin. This constitutes a justified interest pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (f) DSGVO.If your browser does not support web fonts, a standard font is used by your computer.Further information about handling user data, can be found at https://developers.google.com/fonts/faq and in Google’s privacy policy at https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.MediaIf you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.Contact formsUsers can submit a contact form to get information about our organization, programs, services, or general information. We collect name, phone number, email address, IP address and referral URL of the user submitting the form. We also collect the contents of the comments or body of the message to better serve our users.CookiesOur website uses cookies and other related technologies (for convenience all technologies are referred to as "cookies"). Cookies are also placed by third parties we have engaged. Below inform you about the use of cookies on our website.If you leave a comment, submit a contact form, or submit a donation form on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.What are cookies?A cookie is a small simple file that is sent along with pages of this website and stored by your browser on the hard drive of your computer or another device. The information stored therein may be returned to our servers or to the servers of the relevant third parties during a subsequent visit.What are scripts?A script is a piece of program code that is used to make our website function properly and interactively. This code is executed on our server or on your device.What is a webbeacon?A web beacon (or a pixel tag) is a small, invisible piece of text or image on a website that is used to monitor traffic on a website. In order to do this, various data about you is stored using web beacons.ConsentWhen you visit our website for the first time, we will show you a pop-up with an explanation about cookies. You do have the right to opt-out and to object against the further use of non-functional cookies.You can also disable the use of cookies via your browser, but please note that our website may no longer work properly.Third partiesWe have made agreements about the use of cookies with other companies that place cookies. However, we cannot guarantee that these third parties handle your personal data in a reliable or secure manner. Parties such as Google are to be considered as independent data controllers. We recommend that you read the privacy statements of these companies.Information about the cookies we useWhen accessing our website, the following cookies are stored in your browser’s cache. If you choose refuse/opt-out of cookies, non-essential will be removed. Name: _gaDomain: amandafoundation.orgProvider: Google AnalyticsPurpose: Analytical cookie – This cookie is also used by Google Analytics to distinguish between different visitors to the website.Name: _gidDomain: amandafoundation.orgProvider: Google AnalyticsPurpose: Analytical cookie – This cookie is used by Google Analytics to configure the request rate generated and to distinguish users of the website from each other.Name: _gat_gtag_UADomain: amandafoundation.orgProvider: Google AnalyticsPurpose: Analytical cookie – This cookie is used by Google in connection with the use of the Google Tag Manager, in order to download the codes introduced within the tag manager and to prepare them together with the Google Analytics tracking tool.Name: cookieconsent_statusDomain: amandafoundation.orgProvider: Amanda FoundationPurpose: Functional cookie – This cookie stores the dismissal of the cookie consent banner.Name: frDomain: facebook.comProvider: Facebook PixelPurpose: Analytical cookie: This cookie is used by Facebook in connection with the us of the Facebook Pixel in order to connect your visit to the Facebook servers.Embedded content from other websitesElements on this site may include embedded content from other websites. Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.AnalyticsWe collect analytical data through our hosting provider and may collect analytical data through the use of plugins on this website. This data is used to determine traffic flow, and help to analyze advertising campaigns and is not sold to third parties.Who we share your data withWe do not share or sell your personal data with 3rd party vendors or providers other than for the purpose of processing donations. The information provided may include name, company name, email address, and phone number with 3rd party vendor/provider.What rights you have over your dataYou can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.Where we send your dataVisitor information may be checked through an automated spam detection service.SecurityWe take steps to protect your personal data including limiting access to staff and the use of encryption methods such as SSL connections as well as other measures to ensure security.Third party websitesThis privacy statement does not apply to third party websites connected by links on our website. We cannot guarantee that these third parties handle your personal data in a reliable or secure manner. We recommend you read the privacy statements of these websites prior to making use of these websites.ChildrenOur website is not designed to attract children and it is not our intent to collect personal data from children under the age of consent in their country of residence. We therefore request that children under the age of consent do not submit any personal data to us.Amendments to this privacy statementWe reserve the right to make amendments to this privacy statement. It is recommended that you consult this privacy statement regularly in order to be aware of any changes. In addition, we will actively inform you wherever possible.Our contact informationThe Amanda Foundation351 North Foothill Road, Beverly Hills, CA 90210(310) 278-2935
